### Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/divesh-kubal (LinkedIn)

## Top Skills

Chatbot

Artificial Neural Networks Artificial Intelligence

### Honors-Awards

Mashable Online News Dataset Contest

**SPOT Award** 

STAR PERFORMER

**Upcoming Talent Award** 

#### **Publications**

A Survey on Word Embedding Techniques and Semantic Similarity for Paraphrase Identification

Application of machine learning algorithms to predict crop yield in precision agriculture, Tamil Nadu, India

Optimization of Schizophrenia Diagnosis Prediction using Machine Learning Techniques

Poster Presentation on Creation Of Local Decision Tree, Navi Mumbai, Mumbai

Application of Various Graph Kernels for Finding Molecular Similarity in Ligand Based Drug Discovery, American University, Bulgaria

# **Divesh Kubal**

Manager - Analytics and Marketing Automation

Mumbai, Maharashtra, India

## Summary

Experienced in Machine Learning and Deep Learning techniques. Have been working in Artificial Intelligence domain related with Natural Language Processing (NLP), Computer Vision and Data Analysis.

Successfully implemented and optimized various Deep Learning modules, word embedding techniques, Object detection and recognition.

Proficient in various Deep Learning architectures like CNN, Faster RCNN, LSTM, Transfer Learning.

Worked in Brain Cognitive Science domain for prediction of Schizophrenia mental disorder diagnosis

Proficient in Python and R programming. Experience in working with packages like TensorFlow, sklearn, NumPy, SciPy, matplotlib, Keras, Pandas, ggplot2, e1071, MASS.

# Experience

eClerx

Data Scientist (Center of Excellence - Machine Learning)
March 2018 - Present

Mumbai, Maharashtra, India

### GRAYMATRIX SOLUTIONS PRIVATE LIMITED

Artificial Intelligence System Analyst December 2016 - March 2018 (1 year 4 months)

- 1. Designed Conversation Engine architecture.
- Developed Deep Learning models using Convolutional Neural Networks (CNN) and Long Short Term Memory (LSTM) for Natural Language Understanding and semantic similarity (Paraphrase Identification)
- 3. Designed a module which can automatically extract, validate parameters from a user's complex queries.

4. Successfully implemented logic for handling multiple user queries simultaneously for scalability purpose and reduced time complexity.

Alexis Group Internship from Alexis Group August 2015 - August 2015 (1 month) Online

- Wrote many technical papers
- Surveyed many people on topics of science and technology as well as on general topics through various medias like online surveys, audio and video.

Bhugol GIS, IIT Internship July 2015 - July 2015 (1 month) IIT Mumbai

- Completed internship in IIT Bombay on an Android Application named Gram App.
- Implemented complete GPS functionality in the android application as a team leader
- · Also worked on building GUI

## Education

Bhartiya Vidya Bhavans Sardar Patel Institute of Technology Munshi Nagar Andheri Mumbai

Master of Technology - MTech in Artificial Intelligence, Deep Learning, Natural Language Processing, Machine Learning, Computer Vision · (2016 - 2018)

University of Mumbai

B.E., COMPUTER SCIENCE AND ENGINEERING · (2012 - 2016)